ineteconomics.org 2013-05-19

# Privacy Policy | Institute for New Economic Thinking (INET)

_Last updated: June 25, 2010_

The Institute for New Economic Thinking ("INET") is committed to protecting the privacy and security of visitors to our websites, whether registered or unregistered. Here is our online privacy policy for information collected through our website and through email lists  

Use of our websites is not restricted to registered users, and we expect to provide a robust experience to all users.  

If you have any questions about our privacy policy, please fell free to email us at: [info@ineteconomics.org](mailto:info@ineteconomics.org?subject=Privacy%20Policy)

What INET Will Do with Your Information

The Institute for New Economic Thinking will not sell or share the personal information you provide or we collect through our website to any unaffiliated organization without your permission, with the following exceptions. We may share personal information with third parties who provide services, such as website hosting or other services of an administrative or technical nature, solely for the purpose of providing such services and subject to confidentiality obligations. In addition, we reserve the right to disclose personal information about visitors: if we believe in good faith that the law permits it; to protect the rights, property, safety or security of INET, our visitors, our registered users or the public; to respond to an emergency; or to enforce any terms of use agreement governing use of a website controlled or operated by us.  

From time to time, we may send you information from other like-minded organizations whose products or services we think subscribers might find interesting, but we do not exchange, trade, rent, or give email lists to unaffiliated third parties.  

### If You Sign Up for One of Our Mailing Lists

The Institute for New Economic Thinking is committed to providing timely updates to our users by email. We will request information from you to enhance our ability to customize our communications with you so you get the information you want. We will collect relevant contact information and enable you to self-select the type of information that you'd like to receive. You will be able to unsubscribe from communications you receive from us by following the directions included in each such communication.  

### If You Submit Information to Public Areas of an INET Site

Please be aware that if you decide to disclose personally identifiable information on a publicly-accessible areas of an INET site (such as comments on the blog), this information may become public. The Institute for New Economic Thinking does not control the acts of other visitors to its sites, so please be cautious when deciding to reveal personal information a public area of any site. Please contact us if you believe a visitor to an INET site is improperly collecting or using information about you or other users.  

### Cookies

A cookie is a small piece of information that a website can store on a computer and later use to recognize a user. The purpose of cookies is to enhance your ability to receive the information you want. INET may use cookies to enhance the experience of users. A session cookie expires when a user closes the browser in which the Institute's website was viewed. As with all cookies, users can personalize their browser settings to reject session cookies.  

### IP Addresses and Log File Data

IP addresses are ID numbers for the location of your computer or network on the internet. Log files are recordings of the traffic to and from a server. INET's servers log IP addresses for systems administration and troubleshooting. We track page hits in the aggregate to track the popularity of pages that people visit. With that information we can improve the quality of the site.  

### Children's Privacy

The Institute for New Economic Thinking is concerned about the safety and privacy of children online. Because of this, we will make all efforts to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). COPPA and its accompanying FTC regulations establish United States federal law that protects the privacy of children using the Internet. We do not and will not knowingly contact or collect personal information from children under 13. Our site is not intended to solicit information of any kind from children under 13, and we will develop our site with the capacity to block acceptance of information from children under 13 whenever age-related information is requested.  

It is possible that by fraud or deception by others we may receive information given to us or pertaining to children under 13. If we are notified of this, as soon as we verify the information, we will immediately obtain parental consent or else delete the information from our servers. If you want to notify us of our receipt of information by children under 13, please do so by e-mailing us at [info@ineteconomics.org](mailto:info@ineteconomics.org?subject=Children%27s%20Privacy)  

### Security

The Institute for New Economic Thinking has measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of visitor personally identifiable information that is under our control. For example, only select INET staff and contracted individuals have access to personally identifiable information provided by visitors to non-public areas of our sites. We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving sensitive personal and financial data from our site. Please note, however, that security breaches can occur even if reasonable steps are taken to prevent such breaches; for example, we cannot guarantee that information provided through our sites will not be illegally accessed on our servers or intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet. Please contact us if you believe there has been any breach of the security of our sites.  

### Please Note

We plan to regularly update and add new features to our websites. Because of this, INET expects to revise its privacy policy as its site develops. Such amendments will be posted in the privacy policy section of the site. You can determine whether privacy policy has been modified since your last visit by checking the "Last updated" legend at the top of the policy. As stated above, the spirit of this policy will be maintained, and our policy to never sell, exchange, rent, trade, or give email lists to unaffiliated third parties will never be altered. Our website links to other like-minded websites, but is not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of those websites.
